<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Shen</title>
    <link>https://www.tomzshen.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tom Shen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.tomzshen.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on The Death and Life of Great American Cities</title>
      <link>https://www.tomzshen.com/blog/2020/02/notes-on-the-death-and-life-of-great-american-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tomzshen.com/blog/2020/02/notes-on-the-death-and-life-of-great-american-cities/</guid>
      <description>(Disclaimer: this is a work-in-progress, and will be updated as I read the book.)
 The Death and Life of Great American Cities (1961) by Jane Jacobs  The uses of sidewalks What makes neighborhoods safe and unsafe? The answer is generally not the presence of police (a neighborhood where you frequently see police officers is certainly not a safe neighborhood). Instead, neighborhoods depend on having people watching the street. These people can be hired (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacks</title>
      <link>https://www.tomzshen.com/blog/2020/01/backpacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tomzshen.com/blog/2020/01/backpacks/</guid>
      <description>(Disclaimer: this is an unedited rough draft.)  I promised to not write about backpacks, but here we are. Let&#39;s just get all of this out of my system now so that I never have to write about backpacks again. I&#39;m going to talk about backpacks that I use, backpacks that I recommend, and backpacks that I do not.  I&#39;m mostly interested in bags that are useful for EDC and for one-bag urban travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Site</title>
      <link>https://www.tomzshen.com/blog/2020/01/this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tomzshen.com/blog/2020/01/this-site/</guid>
      <description>Update (2020.03.07): This site now uses Hugo. Turns out having to manually sync head tags and nav between multiple pages is no fun. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy fast (compared to Jekyll), but somehow manages to be even more confusing to use.
This site is an experiment in how far I can get in making a personal site without relying on any build tools/libraries, just using raw HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
At first, I was just gonna use Jekyll, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done for previous versions of this site, but when I took a look at the repo for the first time in a few months, I saw there were two libraries that I needed to upgrade to fix security vulnerabilities, and I just could not be bothered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.tomzshen.com/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tomzshen.com/photos/</guid>
      <description> I post phone photos on Instagram.  Here are some photos that I&#39;ve taken:  Kyoto, 2019   Kyoto, 2019   Kyoto, 2019   Tokyo, 2019   Lausanne, 2018   Paris, 2018   Paris, 2018   Tokyo, 2017   Singapore, 2017   Singapore, 2017   Napa, 2017   Nanjing, 2017 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>